<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Ognyan's Blog - posts</title><link href="https://ogenev.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ogenev.github.io/feeds/posts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://ogenev.github.io/</id><updated>2018-12-11T23:28:00+02:00</updated><subtitle>Junior Data Scientist</subtitle><entry><title>My First Blog Post</title><link href="https://ogenev.github.io/first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-11T23:28:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-12-11T23:28:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ognyan Genev</name></author><id>tag:ogenev.github.io,2018-12-11:/first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, here is my first blog post! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For nearly half a year I have begun to engage in &lt;strong&gt;data science&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;machine learning&lt;/strong&gt;, and I really think that's what I would like to do for the future. I've always liked computers since I was a kid, I even remember that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, here is my first blog post! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For nearly half a year I have begun to engage in &lt;strong&gt;data science&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;machine learning&lt;/strong&gt;, and I really think that's what I would like to do for the future. I've always liked computers since I was a kid, I even remember that at one point I wanted to become a cracker, even my nickname was CrAcKMaStEr :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was really fun, I also bought some books for C++ and Java and I started to learn to program. But afterwards something changed, maybe because of the environment I was in, I started to be interested in fitness and started to spend more time in the gym. Programming remained in the background, but I always enjoyed spending a lot of time in front of the computer, I feel like I can do it for all eternity and I will not get tired :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the enthusiasm for the gym subsided, I began to engage in &lt;strong&gt;online poker&lt;/strong&gt;. A lot of people do not know what it really takes to be a professional online poker player, maybe I have to write a special blog post about it. I was making really good money, but I always knew it was not my path, and I felt I had to change something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of 2016, with a friend of mine, we decided to make an &lt;strong&gt;online reservation platform&lt;/strong&gt; for beauty and SPA salons here in &lt;strong&gt;Bulgaria&lt;/strong&gt; (JOLYY was the name of our company). 
We made a lot of mistakes in the process, but that is quite normal, given that we had no experience. &lt;strong&gt;Bitcoin and cryptocurrency&lt;/strong&gt; craze caught up with us and we decided to resurrect the project and go global by making ICOs and trying to find funding from the crypto community. But we met a wall and that's when the Bitcoin bubble burst. After all, the project failed two years later, but the things we learned about online business are very valuable and really irreplaceable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here I am, enthusiastic about data science, machine learning and AI! I know I have a long way to go, and I have a lot to learn, so I decided to share my progress and the things I'm going through. And what better way to do that than starting to write my own blog posts?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="data science"></category><category term="story"></category><category term="machine learning"></category></entry></feed>